<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>[An Almanack and prognostication for 1576]</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1576</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A69014</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 401.8</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S119483</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">23380691</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 23380691</idno>
            <idno type="VID">20127</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A69014)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 20127)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1392:11 or 1826:7)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>[An Almanack and prognostication for 1576]</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[5+] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Imprynted at London in Powles Churchyard, by Richarde Watkyns, and Iames Roberts,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1576]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>T.p. lacking; title suggested by STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon; date of publication suggested by STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>"Formerly included under STC 402 and 20428"--STC (2nd ed.).</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: lacking all except signatures C₁ and C₈.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Cambridge University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Almanacs, English.</term>
               <term>Ephemerides.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:20127:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 55 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:20127:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 55 -->
            <div type="part">
               <p>
                  <gap reason="missing" extent="1+ pages">
                     <desc>〈1… pages missing〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" extent="3 letters">
                     <desc>•••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>perate ſeaſon. The xvj. colde and drie. The xvij. conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuing temperate. The xviij. white clowds with blaſts. The xix. hote, tempeſtuous, and wyndie.</p>
               <p>☾ Laſt quarter the xx. day, at vij. a clocke, xxxviij. min. before noone, moderate for heate, with likelyhoode of rayne. The xxj. raine and wynde. The xxij. colde, clow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die, and moyſt. The xxiij. warme and fayre. The xxiiij. drie and ſultrie hote. The xxv. wyndie blaſtes and drie. The xxvj. coole and fayre. The xxvij. warme, with wette wyndes.</p>
               <p>
                  <g ref="char:Moonnew">●</g> Newe Moone the xxviij. day at foure a clocke xxxviij. minutes before noone, wyndie, with warme ſhowers among. The xxix. inclyned to moyſture as before. The xxx. dropping nowe and then. The xxxj. warme and cleare.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>¶ Of Iune.</head>
               <p>The firſt day, wyndes and tempeſt, and like to thun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der. The ſeconde coole and clowdie.</p>
               <p>☽ Firſt quarter the thirde day, at vj. a clock, xxxiij. mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nutes in the euening, drie. fayre and temperate. The iiij. ſome varietie. The v. wetre and wyndie. The vj. glummie and likelyhoode of moyſture. The vij. broken clowdes ouer heade. The viij. ſet to rayne. The nynth, holding vp and drie. The tenth, coole with chaunge of ayre.</p>
               <p>
                  <g ref="char:Moonround">❍</g> Full Moone the xi. day at viij. a clocke ix. minutes in the morning, hote and ſmoulrie, threatning thunder. The xij. continuing diſpoſed as before. The xiij. fayre and temperate. The xiiij. alteration of weather. The xv. as before, wynde weſterly. The xvj. coole and clow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>die for rayne. The xvij. moyſture and blaſts. The xviij. temperate and lyke to rayne.</p>
               <p>☾ Laſt quarter the xix. day, halfe an houre before high noone, very warme and drie, with whyte clowdes fly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing.
<pb facs="tcp:20127:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 56 -->The xx. continuing ſo diſpoſed. The xxj. temperate and drie. The xxij. fayre with whyte clowdes diſper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed. The xxiij. lyke diſpoſition as before. The xxiiij. warme, and bent to rayne. The xxv. continuing as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore.</p>
               <p>
                  <g ref="char:Moonnew">●</g> Newe Moone the xxvj. day, about halfe an houre af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter high noone, thicke blacke clowdes importing rayne. The xxvij. abyding dyſpoſed to moyſture. The xxviij. warme and fayre. The xxix. more temperate from heat. The xxx. drie, and cooler than before.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>¶ Of Iulye.</head>
               <p>The firſt day, drie weather, and temperate. The ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>conde warme and cleare ſkyes.</p>
               <p>☽ Firſt quarter the thirde day, at two a clocke xxviij. minutes in the morning, drie and ſmoultie ho<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>. The fourth, moyſture, and wynde Northerly. The v. diſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to moyſture. The vj. calme, quiet, and temperate. The vij. troubleſome, wynde, lightning, and thunder. The viij. ſullie hote as before. The ix. more remiſſe of heate.</p>
               <p>
                  <g ref="char:Moonround">❍</g> Full Moone the x. day at x. a clocke, xivj. minutes at night, coole and temperate, with drougth. The xj. lyke diſpoſition as before. The xij. warme and wyndie. The xiij. lyke diſpoſed. The xiiij. clowdes <gap reason="illegible" extent="6 letters">
                     <desc>••••••</desc>
                  </gap>ing rayne. The xv. colde, and clowdie for ſhowers. The xvj. conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuing lyke, but warmer. The xvij. ſmall miſtings ſome<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>time. The xviij. warme with blaſtes.</p>
               <p>☾ Laſt quarter, the xix. day, about halfe an houre and more before one a clocke in the morning, fayre and tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perate. The xx. coole and lyke to rayne. The xxj. cléere, with wynde Weſterlye. The xxij. fayre ſkie, and varia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble. The xxiij. ſtormie rayne. The xxiiij. lyke to holde as before.</p>
               <p>
                  <g ref="char:Moonnew">●</g> Newe Moone the xxv. day, at vij. a clocke, xiiij. min. at
<pb facs="tcp:20127:2"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 57 -->
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:20127:3"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 57 -->
                  <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                     <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <gap reason="missing" extent="1+ pages">
                     <desc>〈1… pages missing〉</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb facs="tcp:20127:3" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                  <!-- PDF PAGE 57 -->yorkeſhire. at Rithin in Wales.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>¶ Faires in Nouember.</head>
               <p>THe ſeconde daye, at Blechinglye. at Kingſton. at Maxfeelde in Cheſhyre.</p>
               <p>The v. day, being S. Leonardes day. at Standley. at Newport ponde. at Trigney in Cornewale. at Sal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forth. at Leſforde in Lancaſhire.</p>
               <p>The x day, being Benets day, at Lenton.</p>
               <p>The xi being S. Martins day. at Marlborow. at Douer.</p>
               <p>The xij. daye, being Paterne daye. at S. Edmondeſbu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rie. at Gilforde.</p>
               <p>The xvij. being S. Hughes daye, (and the beginning of the Queenes Maieſties reygne that nowe is, whome God long preſerue.) at Harlowe. at Hyde.</p>
               <p>The xix. day, being S. Elizabeths day. at Horſham.</p>
               <p>The xx. being S. Edmonds day. at Hide. at Ingerſtone.</p>
               <p>The xxiij. day, being S. Clements day. at Sandwich.</p>
               <p>The xxx. day, being S. Andrew the Apoſtles day. at Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingborough. at Rocheſter. at Peterfeelde. at May<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den heade. at Warington in Lancaſhire. at Bewd<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ley. at Barefoord in yorkeſhire. at Oſcſtry in Wales.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>¶ Fayres in December.</head>
               <p>THe fift day, which is S. Nicholas euen. at Pluckley.</p>
               <p>The vj. day, which is S. Nicholas day. at Spalding. at Smock. at Exceter. at Arndale. at Northwitch in Cheſhire.</p>
               <p>The vij. day, being Octa. of S. Andrewe. at Sandhurſt.</p>
               <p>The viij. daye, being the Concept. of Marie. at Clitherall in Lancaſhire. at Malpas in Cheſhire.</p>
               <p>The xxix. daye, at Canterburie. at Saliſburie.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>¶ Imprynted at London in Powles Churchyard, by Richarde Watkyns, and Iames Roberts.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
